#### Contact

joshi.sujit@outlook.com +91 87881 48805

Currently in Bengaluru, originally from Pune.

# Sujit Joshi

A service designer & researcher brimming with curiosity and a cando attitude, adept at systems thinking and carefully balancing user needs with business practicalities. Eagerly takes ownership, sparks collaboration, upholds the value of research, and goes out of the way to ensure project success.

#### Portfolio

https://sujitjoshi.com

# **Work Experience**

# Philips India Ltd. Service Designer II Mar 2023 to present

Service Designer I

Sep 2021 to Mar 2023 Bengaluru, India

## Service Designer II

- Scoped and led service design & research projects across various business verticals as part of an internal-facing consultative business transformation team in the healthcare technology
- Articulated the value of service design & research to C-suite members & program heads.
- Worked end-to-end, across all stages of projects, to find opportunities, design interventions, test, implement, and evaluate new service experiences for healthcare professionals and patients.
- Conducted extensive qualitative research (on-field & virtual) with participants across the globe, communicated insights through various data visualization techniques.
- Designed end-to-end service experiences, customer journeys, UX prototypes, marketing assets, and non-digital touchpoints.
- Facilitated workshops among cross-functional teams to foster alignment.
- Quantified CX impact via NPS, CSAT, modified versions of SUS scores to support iterative implementation of new experiences in key service moments of customer, user, and patient journeys.
- Hosted internal workshops and 'clinics' to expand strategic & service thinking within the Bangalore design team on popular demand.
- Started a Generative AI and Mixed Reality interest group of six members to find ways to improve overall customer experience, patient outcomes, & workflow efficiencies within Philips.

#### Studio 5B

**Dr. Reddy's Laboratories** Nov 2020 to Jul 2021 Mumbai, India

## Service Designer

- Worked closely with UX designers, researchers, business stakeholders in collaborative, cross functional teams during internship.
- Conducted research for new patient-facing services and identified opportunities to improve core internal processes
- Created end to end service blueprints to map as-is and future journeys, synthesized impactful insights from data gathered through primary and secondary research.
- Facilitated design thinking, needs-gathering, and brand strategy workshops.

# MIT World Peace University Jul 2020 to Oct 2020 Pune, India

# Visiting Faculty- UX Prototyping

 Taught UX Prototyping to third year undergraduates through project-based learning. Expanded class to include discovery and evaluative research techniques based on students' requests.

#### Research Methods

- Interviews
- Diary studies
- Shadowing
- Secondary research
- Method acting
- Heuristics evaluation
- Service pilots
- A/B tests
- · Usability studies

#### Workshops facilitated

- Design Thinking trainings
- Co-design
- Brainstorming sessions
- Research alignment workshops

#### Artifacts created

- Service blueprints
- User experience and journey maps
- · Discussion guides
- Value network maps
- Storyboards
- Process flow diagrams
- System diagrams
- Stakeholder maps
- Workshop materials
- 2D and stop motion animations
- Physical prototypes
- · Web apps
- Interactive data visualizations

#### Languages

- English
- Marathi
- Hindi

#### **Panorama Innovation**

Jul 2019 to Mar 2020 Chicago, United States

## Service Designer and User Researcher

- · Worked with clients in health insurance, city governance, and education fields in an innovation consulting role, bringing service design and research perspective to innovation programs.
- Worked end to end, from conducting discovery research, designing new solutions, supporting pilots of interventions to evaluate impact.
- Facilitated design thinking training workshops, co-design workshops, and research-alignment workshops.
- Planned and conducted in-depth primary and secondary research (discovery and evaluative), created discussion guides, synthesized impactful insights.
- Created research tools such as online diary studies and card sorts.

# Various organizations

Jul 2015 to March 2020

#### + 5 more relevant experiences:

Freelance Designer, Data Visualization Designer and Developer, Researcher, Teaching Assistant, and Product Design & Engineering Intern

# Education

# School of the Art Institute of Chicago

Jul 2017 to May 2019 Chicago, United States

# Master of Design, Designed Objects

Service Design and Research

# Savitribai Phule Pune University

Jul 2012 to May 2016 Pune, India

# **Bachelor of Engineering**

Mechanical Engineering

# Recognition

#### iF Design Awards

April 2023

# iF Design Award 2023

Service Design Category

Associated with Philips India Ltd

#### MIT Media Lab

Jul 2017 to May 2019 Chicago, United States

# Winning Team, Design.A.Hack.a.thon

MIT Media Lab & UC San Diego Design Lab

# **Exhibitions**

# School of the Art Institute of Chicago

**Polling Place** 

Jan 2020 Chicago, United States Alumni Exhibition in collaboration with Aimee Martinez Created new perspective to think about democracies and polling

# School of the Art

Institute of Chicago May 2019

Chicago, United States

### **Graduate Thesis Exhibition**

Nava Savhita: An exploration of alternate histories to contribute to innovation in Ayurveda and decolonization of indigenous sciences